BANOBE PASCAL

SENIOR FRONTEND DEVELOPER

AREAS OF EXPERTISE

HTML / CSS / SASS

JavaScript / TypeScript

React.js / React-Hooks

Redux / MobX / Context

Node.js / Express

SQL / NOSQL

Git / Github

CI / CD

Bash / Shell CLI

Linux / Windows

Bug Reports

PERSONAL SKILLS

Self-starter

Team player

Flexible & adaptable

Good Communication

Problem-solving

PERSONAL DETAILS

Name: Banobe Pascal

Mobile: +256 706 537 427

Email: <u>banobepascal@gmail.com</u>

Portfolio: <u>devpascal.netlify.app</u>

Github: github.com/banobepascal

Linkedin.com/in/banobe-pascal-36196519a

PROFILE

I'm Banobe Pascal a dedicated and efficient frontend developer with experience in JavaScript, TypeScript, React.js, React-Redux, MobX, Node.js, Express.js and SQL/NoSQL. I am very passionate about problem-solving, satisfying the users with the best experience as well as the best delivery service. I possess strong attention to detail, well-developed time management skills, and the ability to complete all projects within schedule and in a timely manner.

OBJECTIVE

To be able to use my expert problem-solving and communication skills to work with teams and companies developing products and tools people love to use.

KEY SKILLS AND COMPETENCES

- Experience in working through all stages of a development project.
- Understanding of Object-Oriented Programming.
- Ability to manage own projects and portfolios.
- Good administration and organizational skills.
- A strong understanding of professional software development practices.
- Able to communicate complex issues to a large range of stakeholders at all levels.
- Have exposure to requirements definition and concept of workflow/reporting.
- Integration of third-party APIs to front-end and back-end.
- Knowledge of differing methodologies i.e. Agile and Scrum.
- Familiarity with CI/CD technologies and workflow (TravisCI, Code Climate).
- Knowledge of unit and integration testing with Mocha / Chai and Jest.
- Experience in pair programming and teamwork at all levels.

EDUCATION

Higher Diploma in Software Engineering - June 2018 - Sept 2021. (Aptech Computer Education, Uganda)

Build web apps with ReactJS

(OpenClassrooms)

Learn Programming With JavaScript

(OpenClassrooms)

Andela, Kigali (Bootcamp) - Sept 2019 - Oct 2019.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Senior Frontend (React) developer at Lendsmart - December 2021 - Present .

Freelance software developer - Aug 2018 - Present.

RECENT WORK AND PROJECTS

SENIOR FRONTEND DEVELOPER AT LENDSMART: https://lendsmart.ai/

Lendsmart's end-to-end solution automates & digitizes lending and home buying operations for banks, credit unions, and non-bank lenders.

- Lead the onboarding of Allies for community business on to Lendsmart platform.
- Implemented workflows and features for other clients e.g. LoanDepot, Sutton bank, Midwest bank, First community bank and A4CB.
- Integrated third-party APIs e.g. Argyle, Railz, Finicity and Transunion
- Worked with UI/UX engineer to implement new designs from figma into React/Material UI.
- Utilized: JavaScript, TypeScript, React, Redux, GraphlQL, Material UI,

SUPERSWIFT: https://shoprite.dev.cymonzfxip.com/

An online electronic platform for sending and receiving money.

- Implemented sending and receiving money features to beneficiaries.
- Used Jira and Agile methodologies throughout the entire development process.
- Re-designed the entire frontend of SuperSwift and applied responsiveness.
 Utilized: JavaScript, TypeScript, React, Redux, Axios, Cypress

E LEARNER: http://e-learner-live.herokuapp.com/

An online fashion e-commerce platform.

- Used React-router for navigation and giving a user a single-page app experience.
- Implemented Firebase for authentication and firestorm as a database.
- Implemented best coding practices to improve project effectiveness.
- Utilized: JavaScript, React, Redux, React-router, Firebase

TEAMWORK: https://github.com/banobepascal/teamwork

An internal social network for organizations' employees. A project part of the Andela Bootcamp training program.

- Designed front-end with HTML/CSS, JavaScript and font awesome.
- Used Mocha and Chai for unit and integration testing of API.
- Applied DevOps practices i.e. CI/CD with TravisCI and Code Climate.
- Utilized: JavaScript, Nodejs, Express, PostgresQL, Mocha / Chai, TravisCl, Heroku.

PERSONAL PORTFOLIO: https://devpascal.netlify.app
For additional information and project links to Github